[SPEAKER_01]: And they wouldn't accept her.
[SPEAKER_01]: So she had to go to NYU.
[SPEAKER_01]: She went to NYU and it cost me, at that time, I think, $4,000 a year.
[SPEAKER_01]: She's now in San Diego, Chile.
[SPEAKER_01]: She's a Catholic nun.
[SPEAKER_02]: When did you get married?
[SPEAKER_01]: In 32, in Flushing.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, well, right near, in Corona.
[SPEAKER_02]: What is Sam Mealy's connection again?
[SPEAKER_01]: My sister's oldest boy, my nephew.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's been quite a bit older than you then, right?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, he's younger than I am.
[SPEAKER_02]: He, she, the sister?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh yeah, my sister's in her eighties, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's kind of hard to believe Mealy would be a nephew.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh yeah, Sam, not Sammy.
[SPEAKER_01]: Close to 50 I guess, somewhere near there, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Just to finish off a few odds and ends here, between 1947 and 1951 when you went to Cleveland, were you managing those years?
[SPEAKER_01]: I managed in Tampa and then I went up with Al Lopez at Indianapolis for one year and then Bucky Wallace asked Al if I'd go over to Cincinnati with him.
[SPEAKER_01]: I coached Bucky in Cincinnati and then they let Bucky go the first year.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Luke Sewell took over.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I stayed with Luke another year, then went and joined Al in Cleveland.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I coached for...
[SPEAKER_01]: I managed to hear one year, I coached three years.
[SPEAKER_01]: One at A&M, two at Cincinnati, then joined Al and stayed with Al.
[SPEAKER_01]: Cleveland, Chicago, and then I went... Al quit.
[SPEAKER_01]: I went with Mayo Smith at Detroit.
[SPEAKER_02]: You were 56 when he went to Chicago?
[SPEAKER_01]: I went with him, yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: I went with him.
[SPEAKER_02]: And then he quit Chicago and...
[SPEAKER_01]: A.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, around 62 or 63 somewhere.
[SPEAKER_01]: 59, yes.
[SPEAKER_01]: Of course, he stayed on a little longer.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then I stayed there with Stanky for a year, and then I left him and
[SPEAKER_01]: and went with Mayo Smith at Detroit, 68-7-68.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then I went back with Al again, 69, and Al came back to manage White Sox again and then took sick.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that was the end of it, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: What was your biggest thrill in baseball to an extent out of all the years?
[SPEAKER_01]: As I say, getting that 6 for 6 was a great thrill for me in 9 innings.
[SPEAKER_01]: At that time there were only 4 or 5 guys that had done it.
[SPEAKER_01]: And there was only Wilbur Robertson was the only one that had 7 for 7.
[SPEAKER_01]: I think one of the Alou boys, not Alou, but... A chap named Garcia Gutierrez.
[SPEAKER_01]: Something like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: I know he was a Cuban boy or a Latin boy.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's never been heard of before or since.
[SPEAKER_02]: Happened to get 7 for 7.
[SPEAKER_01]: 7 for 7, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know, I can remember one day in Cincinnati when they had Walker Cooper.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Walter Cooper came up the 7th time in a game, in a 9-in-a-ball game.
[SPEAKER_01]: And we had the club beat 22-3 or something like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the infield was spread way out to give him a base hit.
[SPEAKER_01]: And he dribbled the ball right back to the plate.
[SPEAKER_01]: He had 6 hits?
[SPEAKER_01]: He had 6 or 6 already.
[SPEAKER_01]: He came up the 7th time.
[SPEAKER_01]: And they figured, well, the game was 22.
[SPEAKER_02]: It didn't mean nothing.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the infielders spread out a little bit.
[SPEAKER_01]: Let him hit one through the infield, and he'd dribble him back to the pitcher.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I want to thank you very much for a wonderful interview.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, thanks a lot, Ed.
[SPEAKER_00]: I really enjoyed this.
[SPEAKER_02]: Make a great tape.
[SPEAKER_02]: See, that man was just... As we chuckle, chucklingly, at the Bay Motel in
[SPEAKER_02]: Sarasota, but we're North Sarasota not too far from South Bradenton in Florida on this beautiful winter evening of January 3rd.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's a Thursday the eighth day in our trip 1980 And we had a very interesting day today We didn't see many sites.
[SPEAKER_02]: We had a couple of great interviews Now to begin us
[SPEAKER_02]: Right, we should talk about last night.
[SPEAKER_02]: Would you like to talk about last night?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: Last night we spent in a campground.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was the... Was it the... Spanish Main.
[SPEAKER_02]: Spanish Main, north of Tampa, northeast of Tampa, in Tono Tosasa.
[SPEAKER_02]: Tono Tosasa.
[SPEAKER_02]: Which was only 50 minutes from Busch Gardens.
[SPEAKER_02]: What do you think of that?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, it was the coldest night Florida's experienced in this area in human history.
[SPEAKER_00]: Since the 1940s.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, well, that's almost the same thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was 30 degrees.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was 30 degrees, and we were in our little tent.
[SPEAKER_02]: Of course, the only tenters on the old campground with all these campers and trailers and things.
[SPEAKER_02]: We bundled up in a couple of pairs of underwear and a couple of pairs of outerwear.
[SPEAKER_02]: What kind of caps?
[SPEAKER_02]: Stocking caps, gloves, and a couple of pairs of socks.
[SPEAKER_02]: And we slept beautifully, except Rita had to get up three times to change her bed.
[SPEAKER_02]: She had, incidentally, a space blanket.
[SPEAKER_02]: Tell her about the space blanket.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's one of those blankets that keeps you warm.
[SPEAKER_00]: It talks a lot.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's one of those, and you can use it as a reflector if you want a sun tan.
[SPEAKER_00]: I've carried it in its suitcase for years.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know what made me think of it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Last night after I was tucked in bed, I had to go over and over and over to get it right.
[SPEAKER_00]: It did keep me warm, but I have had better sleep.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't sleep too well myself.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't even have the nerve to put that on tape.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, anyhow, we got up at the crack of dawn, six o'clock.
[SPEAKER_00]: Six o'clock to do nothing.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, we had a cup of coffee.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had a couple of cups of coffee.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Timmy's father opened a cup of coffee.
[SPEAKER_02]: Neighbors were from Illinois.
[SPEAKER_02]: They've come down here to stay for good.
[SPEAKER_02]: About 18 kids and one father and one mother.
[SPEAKER_02]: A little three-year-old was kind of troublesome, but when he went to bed, things were okay.
[SPEAKER_02]: Anyhow, we got up today, and I had called yesterday before we'd gone to Bush Gardens, which we went to yesterday afternoon, which you're supposed to spend the day at, but we had our fill after four hours in the afternoon.
[SPEAKER_02]: I called Tony Cuccinello in Tampa, living down on Beach Street, right on the bay.
[SPEAKER_02]: and arranged for an interview this morning at... First it was 9 o'clock, but then he said the window makers were going to come, so he made it 9.30, and he had to be gone by 11.30 because he was playing golf.
[SPEAKER_02]: We didn't know that the golf was with Al Lopez.
[SPEAKER_02]: In fact, we couldn't find Al Lopez in the phone book.
[SPEAKER_02]: There were a whole page of Lopez's and about half a page of Al Lopez's, but not our Al Lopez.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, anyhow, we learned he lived right down the street from Tony Cuccinello.
[SPEAKER_02]: He has an unlisted phone number.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, anyhow, we arrived at Tony's place.
[SPEAKER_02]: We went in and had...
[SPEAKER_02]: The fog this morning was terrific.
[SPEAKER_02]: You couldn't see the next car for a while.
[SPEAKER_02]: And we got on the Interstate 4, and things got a little bit better then.
[SPEAKER_02]: We heard of a couple of wrecks this morning in this terrible fog.
[SPEAKER_02]: But they say they have these in the wintertime sometimes.
[SPEAKER_02]: We had breakfast at the Waffle House, and it was very nice.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then we went on and got to Tony Cucinello's about 9.30.
[SPEAKER_02]: We were pretty much on time.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was out there waiting for us in kind of a nervous, expectant way, and I parked across the street, and it's a lovely...
[SPEAKER_02]: It's a street right next to the bay.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, it's a Spanish-type house, you know, a kind of a ranch house in the Spanish style, I suppose.
[SPEAKER_02]: And beautiful, sunny, clear day.
[SPEAKER_02]: Temperature's about 22, maybe a little higher by this time.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he was out there with his golfing catlip.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was ready to go right then.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I walked up in the driveway and he introduced myself and we, him and so on.
[SPEAKER_02]: And
[SPEAKER_02]: He said he was kind of nervous and not too cordial at first, actually, but I think that's part of his nervous nature, really.
[SPEAKER_02]: And, yeah, I agreed.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said what he thought he should say, and I agreed.
[SPEAKER_00]: That sounded like a prepared speech, what he started out with.
[SPEAKER_02]: So he says, is that your wife out in the car?
[SPEAKER_02]: And I said, yes, that is she.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he said, well, invite her in.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I said, yes, okay.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I went back and got my paraphernalia, and we came in.
[SPEAKER_02]: And Mrs. Cuccinello was there, and we went into the Florida room.
[SPEAKER_00]: Right.
[SPEAKER_00]: But you didn't know that's what you were in.
[SPEAKER_02]: No, we didn't know that until later.
[SPEAKER_02]: And well, we began, and Mrs. Cuccinello, when she saw that we were taping, she took Rita off to the kitchen.
[SPEAKER_02]: Or was that the North Carolina room?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, no, the kitchen.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was a plain old kitchen.
[SPEAKER_02]: She understood, apparently, that we were making remarks that would need isolated insulation.
[SPEAKER_02]: So we started in and went on for about...
[SPEAKER_02]: I got about...
[SPEAKER_02]: I got almost 90 minutes, about an hour and a half.
[SPEAKER_02]: We turned the first taff over.
[SPEAKER_02]: She said, is that 30 minutes?
[SPEAKER_02]: I said, no, it's 45.
[SPEAKER_02]: We'd gone that long?
[SPEAKER_02]: He was getting warmed up to it.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a little distant at first, not knowing, of course, what I was doing and who I was.
[SPEAKER_00]: The first thing that he started telling you was just like a spiel that he would give somebody.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, it was.
[SPEAKER_02]: I couldn't shut him off.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was automatic, and he ranged over the first ten years before I, which I had about all kinds of questions to ask about, before I could break in.
[SPEAKER_02]: I finally broke in by saying, well, I'd like to check the tape now and see that we are recording because this thing doesn't work too well.
[SPEAKER_02]: So we checked the tape, and we heard ourselves for a little while.
[SPEAKER_02]: And then I was able to pick up with some of the things we'd missed going before, so we did that.
[SPEAKER_02]: We got a little more detail in there.
[SPEAKER_02]: We didn't wind up with Brooklyn or Cincinnati right away.
[SPEAKER_02]: But the tape I have over here, another tape, it's a good... that's about 80 minutes, I suppose.
[SPEAKER_02]: There are a few minutes idle at the end.
[SPEAKER_02]: But all this while, Rita was out with Mrs. Cucinello in the kitchen.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I listed, we had our little happy hour over here at Friar Tuck's, which is nearby to the Bay Motel, which is here on 41, US 41, which is just a little bit north of the central part of, what's this town?
[SPEAKER_02]: Sarasota.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: We're south of Bradenton, north of Sarasota.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now, Jod had done a few things that they talked about, so she would remember.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now, it's all yours.
[SPEAKER_02]: First of all, how they met, where married.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Okay.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, this will encompass some of those other things, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: She was born and brought up in Indianapolis, one of ten children, five girls and five boys.
[SPEAKER_00]: She was the youngest of the five girls.
[SPEAKER_00]: She had an older sister living in Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_00]: and she used to go over to visit her.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, Cuccinella went to visit her sister, and they went over there, and she was engaged to what Tom Hall, who was in the Air Force, or I don't know if he was in then, but anyway, she went over there with him, and she'd go over and visit her sister, and they went over
[SPEAKER_00]: for a wedding.
[SPEAKER_00]: Their nephew was getting married.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so her sister was giving this big shindig for it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she went over with this fellow, she was engaged to this Tom Hall.
[SPEAKER_00]: And when they got over there, she met Tony Cuccinella.
[SPEAKER_02]: We were near an airport.
[SPEAKER_00]: And something just went... And her
[SPEAKER_00]: She said, you know how these things happen.
[SPEAKER_02]: We're over a very big airport.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, time out for a plane.
[SPEAKER_00]: OK. Maybe she had met him before, but this night at this engagement party, it really clicked.
[SPEAKER_00]: And this fellow she was engaged to was very upset.
[SPEAKER_00]: Tom Hall.
[SPEAKER_00]: Tom Hall was very upset.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he wanted to go right back that night.
[SPEAKER_00]: But, uh, is it Claire?
[SPEAKER_00]: Is that his wife's name?
[SPEAKER_00]: Or is that Lopez's wife's name?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, she is, uh... Well, whoever, Mrs. Cuccinella, uh, sister, didn't want him to drive back because they didn't know what he would hurl.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is a, is a Justin wife.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, that isn't who I wanted.
[SPEAKER_00]: Mrs. Cuccinella's sister.
[SPEAKER_00]: didn't want this Tom Hall driving back to Indianapolis, because he was quite upset about the whole thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: So they talked him into staying over another night, and she stayed with him.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean, in those days, yeah, it was all up and above board.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they went back to Indianapolis, and Cooch, as I will now refer to him, because it makes it easier, yeah, Coochie,
[SPEAKER_00]: as she calls him, kept asking her down for the weekend.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she wouldn't always go, but she went down a lot of times.
[SPEAKER_00]: He must have been playing for Cincinnati then.
[SPEAKER_00]: And this was getting this Tom Hall very upset.
[SPEAKER_00]: So finally she decided the only thing to do was to break off the engagement with him.
[SPEAKER_02]: She was an Italian gal herself.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, she's Italian Catholic.
[SPEAKER_00]: He promptly had a nervous breakdown.
[SPEAKER_00]: Tom Hall?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: after she did this.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then she got engaged to Cooch, and then they got married down in Florida, I think she said.
[SPEAKER_00]: In 1932.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then in 1935, they had their first child.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then 23 months – that was a boy, Tony Jr. And then 23 months later, they had a girl.
[SPEAKER_00]: The – I don't know what it's going to mean.
[SPEAKER_02]: A.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, it began with a D. I didn't realize it at first.
[SPEAKER_00]: But anyway, they had a girl, and then the other boy, the younger boy, was much later.
[SPEAKER_02]: M. Forty-five.
[SPEAKER_00]: A. Forty-five.
[SPEAKER_00]: And now, I don't know why, but they moved to her mother's aide this year ago, but they moved and they got a house in Fletcher.
[SPEAKER_02]: M. Did they ever get her name?
[SPEAKER_02]: A.
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: They got a house in Flushing, 146th Street, Flushing.
[SPEAKER_00]: Lived there for years.
[SPEAKER_00]: And this was good because it was near his folks and worked out very well.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so they lived there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I don't quite understand it because she was talking about passing the New York World's Fair and never going there.
[SPEAKER_00]: in 64, but they've been in that house in Tampa for 20 years.
[SPEAKER_00]: They've owned that house.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, what else is there?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, we'll skip by these little inconsistencies.
[SPEAKER_02]: House in Flushing?
[SPEAKER_00]: Was.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had the hot garbage.
[SPEAKER_02]: Okay.
[SPEAKER_02]: The spring training is my next item.
[SPEAKER_00]: All right.
[SPEAKER_00]: The first three years she went to spring training with him until she had a baby.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then
[SPEAKER_00]: the president of whatever club it was, used to arrange a house for them down there at Springtrain, and she took the two kids down there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Except one year, they got as far as Baltimore, and they were staying in a hotel there when Tony, Jr. took sick, and he had this high fever.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they didn't know what was wrong with him.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so they called their doctor back in Flushing, and he said to start giving him barley water.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he said, how could I possibly get it?
[SPEAKER_00]: She said, here I was staying in a hotel, but the hotel made arrangements.
[SPEAKER_00]: The hotel let her use the kitchen to make this barley water for the baby.
[SPEAKER_00]: But she said, the more I thought about it, she said, the more panicky I got.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she said, I finally said to Tony, this year I cannot go.
[SPEAKER_00]: I've got to go back home.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he said, all right.
[SPEAKER_00]: So she said, we got in the car and went back to Flushing, and then he flew down to spring training that year.
[SPEAKER_00]: But she went to spring training every year through the courtesy of the president or the general manager or whoever that got her the house.
[SPEAKER_02]: How about Warren Giles or Larry McPhail?
[SPEAKER_00]: None of those rang a bell.
[SPEAKER_02]: McKeever?
[SPEAKER_00]: I think she said McKeever got from the house every year.
[SPEAKER_02]: The head of the Brooklyn Club, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so they went down there every year.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then when the kids started in school, she didn't go.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now when he was up in Boston, she used to go up there
[SPEAKER_00]: for the two weeks.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were home two weeks and away two weeks.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she'd go up there for the two weeks on by train and then come back to Flushing.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she said, boy, if you don't think that was something.
[SPEAKER_00]: But the kids wanted to see their father, so she'd pack all his stuff up and get on the train, Blossom to Blossom, for two weeks.
[SPEAKER_00]: And when he took off on the road, she'd come back to Flushing.
[SPEAKER_00]: She said, I don't know how I did it.
[SPEAKER_02]: A. I have next to spring training, but you have that covered.
[SPEAKER_02]: Stuck in Baltimore, Nick.
[SPEAKER_00]: M. Yeah, I told you about that.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was a baby in the barley water.
A.
[SPEAKER_02]: Stuck in La Trobe.
[SPEAKER_00]: M. Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, did he play for Pittsburgh or at all?
A.
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: M. Well, why would he be around there?
[SPEAKER_00]: A.
[SPEAKER_00]: He could have played in Pittsburgh.
[SPEAKER_00]: M. Well, they were doing something.
[SPEAKER_00]: A.
[SPEAKER_00]: What time of year was it?
[SPEAKER_00]: M. Well, they had both the kids in the car, and they were on their way to Pittsburgh for a game.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the little girl got sick.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had a new car.
[SPEAKER_00]: What month was she born?
[SPEAKER_00]: She was born 23 months after the other one, 35.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I was a 35, so 23 would be about 37.
[SPEAKER_02]: Seven.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was with Boston.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: They're planning to go to Pittsburgh.
[SPEAKER_00]: Okay.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they had their transmission went out.
[SPEAKER_00]: It wouldn't go forward.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he couldn't get it off.
[SPEAKER_00]: His wife got sick and lost control.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, that's because I'd been telling him.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so the only thing he could do was back it up.
[SPEAKER_00]: way it would go, and he backed it onto the side of the road.
[SPEAKER_00]: The kid, the girl was in the car, throwing up madly all over everything.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had to walk a mile to get help.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said it would take a week to fix it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I think she said the girl was about five at that time.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they were...
[SPEAKER_00]: A.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, whenever it was, the girl was five.
[SPEAKER_00]: All right.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were friendly with Lopez's then, because Lopez came and got them.
[SPEAKER_02]: M. Al Lopez.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's the Hall of Famer, Al Lopez, who lives about just down the street from them.
[SPEAKER_02]: We didn't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: A.
[SPEAKER_00]: Came and got them.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they have always been very, very friendly with Lopez's.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, many times.
[SPEAKER_02]: And, of course, Al Lopez, as Tony says in the tape, got him to come with Cleveland in those years from 51 to 55 when they won the pennant.
[SPEAKER_02]: And when Lopez went to Chicago, Tony went with him in 56 to 61 when he won the pennant in 59.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he had always been with him.
[SPEAKER_02]: as players and then later on as coach-manager relations.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, they've just always been very, very friendly.
[SPEAKER_02]: Al Lopez's number was not listed in the phone book, so I couldn't call him.
[SPEAKER_00]: How did we know?
[SPEAKER_00]: It might have been if he had looked for that street.
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you know what street he had looked at?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, well... Did you have him listed as Beach?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I had him listed as Mullins.
[SPEAKER_02]: See, and he lives on Beach.
[SPEAKER_02]: In fact, Tony Cuccinello's number is not listed in the phone book.
[SPEAKER_02]: But Tony Cuccinello Jr. was.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I called Tony Cuccinello, Jr. and I got Mrs. Coney Cuccinello.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, she's a delightful girl.
[SPEAKER_02]: She was very pleasant and she gave me the number of Tony Cuccinello, Jr.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think they have two boys and he has done very well.
[SPEAKER_00]: Which one is he now?
[SPEAKER_00]: He's the oldest one.
[SPEAKER_00]: I never found out what he did, but they just bought a condominium over on Treasure Island.
[SPEAKER_00]: She fixed it all up.
[SPEAKER_02]: She sounded very pleasant on the phone.
[SPEAKER_00]: Very nice.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then they rented it out now.
[SPEAKER_00]: They live in Temple Hills, which was great.
[SPEAKER_00]: right near where we were staying.
[SPEAKER_00]: Big, lush housing place with big walls around it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they had the house built to their specifications.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he's the one that's getting all his dad's baseball stuff.
[SPEAKER_02]: He has quite a few pictures there.
[SPEAKER_02]: He took us and Rita, too, into an old garage, or a remodeled garage, which is his, I suppose, his gallery now.
[SPEAKER_00]: When he was gone one time,
[SPEAKER_00]: She had the Florida room enlarged, which is, it's more like a family room, but it's sort of an extension of the living room, dining room, but it's a big, comfortable room, beautiful.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know they have money.
[SPEAKER_00]: And at the same time, she had this other thing built on at the back of their garage, an all-panel
[SPEAKER_00]: for him, for all his stuff, because she doesn't want it cluttering up the house.
[SPEAKER_00]: But the trouble is, they have all this other stuff to hang up, and they have no place to put it, except on the ceiling.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's the first old player's house I've been in where they had a room with all the walls filled with framed 8x10 photographs.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you notice that thing on the door?
[SPEAKER_00]: That baseball player in the door, that was a real clever thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know what it was.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was red with a baseball player on it, and then there was an oil painting of him in his baseball uniform hanging on the wall of the Florida Room.
[SPEAKER_02]: You should have taken a picture.
No.
[SPEAKER_02]: You should have brought the other camera in.
[SPEAKER_02]: But he must have had columns of 10 across and 10 up on each wall.
[SPEAKER_02]: They're all the same size, all autographed.
[SPEAKER_02]: and with little notes to him, including from Jimmy Durante and, of course, my hero, Elvis Presley.
[SPEAKER_02]: He got to know Elvis Presley through Elvis Presley's bodyguard who used to pitch for the Phillies.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know his name, but Tony knew his name, knew him.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was briefly with the Phillies.
[SPEAKER_02]: Apparently he had gotten to know him somewhere, and through him he got to know Elvis Presley.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's why Elvis Presley has a picture in Tony Puccinello's Hall of Fame.
[SPEAKER_00]: The Hall of Fame.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: When Al Lopez was put in the Hall of Fame, and she said she was so happy for him, but she was so crushed for Pucci because she said she just always... Their careers have been so closely linked that apparently they just
[SPEAKER_00]: think of them as twins.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she said, I did say to him, I just thought that when you got in, Gucci would get in.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she said, Al just shrugged his shoulders.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I said, well, I said, you just never know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, and I was telling how you felt about the Hall of Fame and the old-timers and everything, you know, how they were always told you were president of Sabre and all that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was telling her about that campaign that Earl Abel put on that we saw some of the stuff from before he got in.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she was saying that before Lopez went in, there were television men there and reporters from various places and everything.
[SPEAKER_00]: A real campaign before the election.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she said that was the hardest thing in her life that she ever did.
[SPEAKER_00]: was go to all these banquets and dinners for Lotes after that.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I was telling her about what Mrs. Kowalewski said, that if they hadn't given it to Stan while she was alive, while he was alive, she would have taken it and told him where to shove it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she said, that's just the way I feel.
[SPEAKER_00]: So that was the story about the Hall of Fame.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were really upset about that.
[SPEAKER_02]: They thought Tony should have been in there?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, she thought if Lopez got in, he should have.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, that's probably right.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't think either of them should be in there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Great guys as they were and good ballplayers as they were.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because their careers have gone right in tandem.
[SPEAKER_02]: What was Lopez like then?
[SPEAKER_02]: Cuccinella was 280.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she said that Cucci had been offered all I can remember in Chicago.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I think there were two other major league clubs that had offered him jobs as a coach.
[SPEAKER_00]: Puccinelli had more base hits.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had more runs, more home runs, better average.
[SPEAKER_02]: You know, that's right.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had a better record than Al Lopez.
[SPEAKER_02]: Fifteen years, Al was 19, but 15, 14, 17, he had 70, 29 hits.
[SPEAKER_02]: So neither of them should have been in there, but great guys and good ballplayers, there's no question about it.
[SPEAKER_02]: But the idea is that it should be for the elite, you know, if they belong.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, she said she felt when Al got in there, don't you?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, you know why he got in?
[SPEAKER_02]: He was a manager to Bennett Leonard.
[SPEAKER_00]: And because he had a good press relations job.
[SPEAKER_00]: After I said that, she said, you know, she thought, I can see that.
[SPEAKER_00]: She said, because there were television people from all over Florida here taking pictures down there and getting opinions up from Tony and everybody.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she said this was all before he was elected.
[SPEAKER_02]: And it must have been a strain on their relationship, too, I'm sure.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: So she said he was offered three general manager's jobs or... General?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, coaching jobs.
[SPEAKER_00]: Coaching, not manager?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, coaching.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Chicago was one of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: I can't think what the other two were.
[SPEAKER_00]: When was this one?
[SPEAKER_02]: After his career was over?
[SPEAKER_00]: I guess when he was getting towards the end of it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And what about it?
[SPEAKER_00]: And he wouldn't take them because of the...
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, maybe it was after he had worked under Lopez he was offered these jobs.
[SPEAKER_00]: She didn't say.
[SPEAKER_00]: But because of the press, he just would not take that hassle from the press.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said there was no way he was going to cope with that media.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was just easier to get out and stay out.
[SPEAKER_02]: Children, who you haven't mentioned, anything?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I've mentioned some.
[SPEAKER_00]: They have the eldest boy, Tony, and I'm not sure what he does.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he's married, and the girl's just like a daughter to her, and they live in Tampa.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I think they have two boys.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then there was a daughter.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, she was born in, what, 35?
[SPEAKER_00]: She would be born in 37.
[SPEAKER_00]: She went to NYU and got her education, then taught in a high school up there in Long Island for quite a while.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then there was something about she came down to Florida or something and taught in Florida for a while.
[SPEAKER_00]: and took an NETA test or something they put in, and she passed it all but the art.
[SPEAKER_02]: And she was furious.
[SPEAKER_00]: So then she went and taught with the Sisters of Notre Dame in a Catholic school.
[SPEAKER_02]: What he told him of that story in the tape was he applied for one of the New York City colleges, Hunter, Queen, and Brooklyn, and... She has her master's.
[SPEAKER_02]: required an 85-point average to get into one of the city schools, and you had 84 points.
[SPEAKER_02]: So she didn't get into a city school like Queens or Hunter or Brooklyn or one of the... Well, it was art that she missed because she's a science teacher.
[SPEAKER_02]: And so she had to go to NYU because of that, at a considerable cost to him, which she wouldn't have had to pay apparently.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I don't know, but whatever he was...
[SPEAKER_00]: It was the art that she failed in, because she was a science teacher.
[SPEAKER_00]: So she taught with this, and then she went home.
[SPEAKER_00]: She was dating this chap, and he was a good Catholic.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they were really getting quite friendly, and she went up to New York to be with the four of her friends.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were very friendly.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she was teaching in Florida for a while.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she came back, and
[SPEAKER_00]: They were having a big cocktail party that night when she came in.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she said, I have news for you.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they said, oh, you're engaged.
[SPEAKER_00]: And her sister-in-law, the one who's married to the eldest brother, said, oh, you got married.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they were joking around and everything.
[SPEAKER_00]: She said, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: She said, I'm going to become a nun.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Mrs. Coogee said, I probably had a heart attack then and there.
[SPEAKER_00]: She said, oh, I was completely shocked.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she went to Marymont, I think she said, and took her vows and went to Columbia.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she was there, I think, two years or something.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then she wrote and said that, I'm sending you a package home, and you'll have to go to the airport and pick it up.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think that must have been their 45th, I don't know if that was their 45th anniversary or what.
[SPEAKER_00]: And her son came up to the door with his wife and his two kids.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then pretty soon her other son came up with his wife, came to the house.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then a niece or nephew from Indiana came with their family.
[SPEAKER_00]: And behind them was the daughter.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that really shook her up.
[SPEAKER_00]: I guess she almost had a heart attack then and there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Mrs. Cucci, because they weren't expecting a daughter from Chile, a nun.
[SPEAKER_00]: She said, don't ever do that to me again.
[SPEAKER_00]: She said, because I just don't think I can take it.
[SPEAKER_02]: She's a nun in Santiago, Chile.
[SPEAKER_00]: She's been down there five years.
[SPEAKER_02]: Tony said that on the tape.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was some kind of an expression of amazement.
[SPEAKER_02]: She's a nun in Chile.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I think the mother was real disappointed.
[SPEAKER_00]: In a way, she was pleased, but in a way, she was disappointed because she was sure she was getting married.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then the younger boy, who works for Metropolitan Life Insurance in Tampa, his wife just divorced him.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I guess it was just final about, they had one little girl.
[SPEAKER_02]: unexpectedly on the other side.
[SPEAKER_02]: So now you're talking about the... Did you talk about the girl, though?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I must have, because I'm down to the youngest son.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then I took over.
[SPEAKER_02]: I talked about the younger son who was born in 45, and Tony talked about him, because he had the job to coach out at Oakland, I believe, and play, maybe.
[SPEAKER_02]: with Casey Stengel in 1946 after his great year at Chicago and almost won the batting, wouldn't have been something to have won the American League batting title, which he almost did, missed by a fraction of a point.
[SPEAKER_02]: But he knew he was through and he couldn't do it because to leave his infant son who was not well, although we don't know what the problems were, physically he was not well.
[SPEAKER_02]: He just couldn't be 3,000 miles away from them, and so he stayed at home and played with the Bushwicks, and actually made $7,000 or $8,000 a year playing semi-pro ball.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now we're talking about the social life.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, the youngest son, I was going to say, he's been keeping his mother up until 2 or 3 in the morning.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did he say that already?
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't think so.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he met this woman who's 31.
[SPEAKER_00]: But she not only has him living with her now,
[SPEAKER_00]: And all his stuff that was stored out in the garage.
[SPEAKER_02]: He stays at the home, right?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he's staying at the home.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that was all his stuff that was out in the garage in those boxes.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he has visiting rights with the little girl on weekends, so they have her too.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she sells it that much.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now their social life, they're very active socially.
[SPEAKER_00]: Cocktail parties and all kinds of big affairs and Rolls Royces and Cadillacs and all.
[SPEAKER_00]: You wouldn't believe it.
[SPEAKER_00]: The man across the street, the doctor across the street had a Rolls, a Mercedes, some German sports car that nobody had ever seen before.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, they just got divorced, too, but that's all right.
[SPEAKER_00]: Maybe he had a heart attack.
[SPEAKER_00]: But they have always been very friendly and social with the Wins, early Wins, and the Bob Lemons.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then she was talking about when they were first married in Flushing, all the single fellas and that used to go over there and play cards.
[SPEAKER_00]: Their wives sometimes, if they were married, sometimes their wives would come.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that's where this one that I didn't know, I can't remember his name, that died, the pauper.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she said he had such a sense of humor.
[SPEAKER_00]: Very friendly with Babe Ruth and his second wife.
[SPEAKER_00]: She didn't know Jane, the first wife.
[SPEAKER_00]: Claire is the second one.
[SPEAKER_00]: She didn't know the Gehrig's as well as she knew Ruth's.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I would imagine that she has always been very social with all the baseball wives.
[SPEAKER_00]: She's just that type.
[SPEAKER_00]: But she said to this day they, lemons and whims and that there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And of course Lopez's who are their best friends.
[SPEAKER_02]: Managing jobs, newspaper writers, anything new there?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_02]: Babe Ruth?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: She said he was a delightful person.
[SPEAKER_00]: She said he was not the boor, the uncouth person that people said he was.
[SPEAKER_00]: She said he was just as delightful as he could be.
[SPEAKER_02]: Cadillac story.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, she has a Cadillac, and they've spent $1,800 getting the body fixed last year.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the whole thing's starting to rust out again.
[SPEAKER_00]: The guy that fixed it's gone out of business.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had that window that the window man was coming.
[SPEAKER_00]: Today?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, they had the window fixed about a month ago.
[SPEAKER_00]: They have Jalousie windows or Jalousie windows.
[SPEAKER_00]: Those are the ones that roll out that I wanted for the attic, you know, that go up at the slant.
[SPEAKER_00]: And after she had it fixed, she went up one day, because she likes fresh air.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she opened the windows, and here there's this big crash bang.
[SPEAKER_00]: She didn't know what had happened.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the next day she found out the whole thing had collapsed, the one that had just been fixed.
[SPEAKER_00]: So she wanted up and down windows put all over the house.
[SPEAKER_00]: And this is what she was trying to get the estimate on today.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, we came there at a time where the window repair people were there.
[SPEAKER_02]: and kind of intervened with our interview a little bit, along with a golf match with Al Oka.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm surprised I got an interview in at all.
[SPEAKER_02]: I really worked it in.
[SPEAKER_02]: How about Windows, the Yankee Scout?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, she said, when she took me out in the room while you were having the interview,
[SPEAKER_00]: He had that card table set up there with all those, did you notice that card table in that room?
[SPEAKER_00]: And all kinds of papers and a blue book on it and everything.
[SPEAKER_00]: She said, oh, that's the scouting material.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't see me as a scout.
[SPEAKER_02]: Still is, huh?
[SPEAKER_02]: That's what she said.
[SPEAKER_02]: I didn't get into that at all.
[SPEAKER_02]: 52 years of marriage.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, they've been married 52 years.
[SPEAKER_02]: Is that all you got to say about that point?
[SPEAKER_02]: A. Yeah, I think.
[SPEAKER_02]: M. How about Tony Lopez?
[SPEAKER_00]: A. Oh, that was so funny.
[SPEAKER_00]: We were at Gasson's, and I was trying to tell her I never could remember the name, and I couldn't think of Cuccinelli's.
[SPEAKER_00]: I keep calling him Antebelli or Antonelli and what's he?
[SPEAKER_00]: Altebelli.
[SPEAKER_02]: M. Not to Mr. Cuccinelli?
[SPEAKER_02]: A.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, but I am myself, and I couldn't think of his name.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I said, you know... M. What is it?
[SPEAKER_00]: Cuccinelli.
[SPEAKER_00]: He lives on that street.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, his name's Tony.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, you know, he's great friends with Lopez.
[SPEAKER_00]: She said, oh, yes, I know who you mean.
[SPEAKER_00]: Mrs. Gaston.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, you're mixing her up.
[SPEAKER_00]: I know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, that's why you asked me about the stories of Tony.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, that's on our couchinello list.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she said, oh, you mean Tony Lopez.
[SPEAKER_02]: That was a Milt Gaston interview later on in the day.
[SPEAKER_02]: Tony Lopez.
[SPEAKER_02]: Got here about 10 children, her family.
[SPEAKER_02]: I told you that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Air Force Colonel.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, that was Tommy Hall.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, he came to visit her.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were getting ready to go to something, and she didn't have her makeup on or her dinner gown because they were going to some big swank up there.
[SPEAKER_00]: They're always going to those.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the doorbell rang, and I don't know whether it was her daughter-in-law that was there and went and said, there's Tommy Hall here to see you.
[SPEAKER_00]: She said I probably passed out then and there.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I got out and put a rope on and went in here.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was him and his wife.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she said I just didn't know how to tell him he was going to take it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she said I was hoping he wouldn't come in.
[SPEAKER_00]: But she said he was dying of cancer, this doctor, and he wanted to see her before he died.
[SPEAKER_02]: There was a doctor?
[SPEAKER_00]: There was a colonel in the Air Force and he was dying of cancer.
[SPEAKER_02]: A guy she didn't marry.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, and he wasn't here before he died.
[SPEAKER_02]: Kind of a morbid purpose.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, we took him another couple of years to die.
[SPEAKER_02]: I have something here about cigars and the bread box.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yes.
[SPEAKER_00]: We were sitting him there coughing, and she started going into the bread box, and she said,
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, she said, I'm not here for something new.
[SPEAKER_00]: She said, this is where I hide my cigarettes.
[SPEAKER_00]: She kept them in her front box or cartons of cigarettes.
[SPEAKER_00]: I thought that was hilarious.
[SPEAKER_02]: What did you think of the house?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, it was a lovely house.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was, it was money.
[SPEAKER_00]: How old were you then?
[SPEAKER_00]: The house itself?
[SPEAKER_00]: I'd say it was probably 20, 25, 30 years old.
[SPEAKER_00]: Describe it here for your benefit.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's always a one-floor plan, like all these things are.
[SPEAKER_00]: You go into a little foyer, and off to the right is the living room, and off to the left is the dining room, and then behind the living room is this floor to room, and the kitchen is off that, to the left, and then the bedrooms are their bedrooms at the back, and then they have two other bedrooms in that house.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then off to the right of the Florida room is this room where Al has all his pictures on, Tony has all his pictures on, and then a garage in front of that.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was the addition that he had built on.
[SPEAKER_00]: That would normally have gone out in the garage that door.
[SPEAKER_00]: But the whole thing reeked of money.
[SPEAKER_00]: You can tell.
[SPEAKER_00]: beautiful fabric covering all the chairs, and the plush carpet, and everything was just so in that house.
[SPEAKER_02]: Were there pictures of players or drawings of players framed around the room?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, some of him.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's what it was.
[SPEAKER_00]: There weren't pictures of him.
[SPEAKER_02]: There weren't pictures always, there were drawings of him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, but they were of him.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were of him, that one oil portrait.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had a Mother of the Year award and a Mother-Father of the Year award up there, and then they had
[SPEAKER_00]: pictures of their children, a lot of pictures of their children out there, and some baseball pro people in that Florida room.
[SPEAKER_02]: This Tony Cuccinella struck me as a very nervous person.
[SPEAKER_02]: As you may have gathered in the interview, he started talking at about 60 miles an hour almost, and I wondered just where he would get through his career before he even had the tape recorder on.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was very nervous, and as Rita said, he seemed to have a prepared speech there, something like Tony Pyatt did back in, well, he read his back in Chicago.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I think I slowed him down a little bit, but he still was quite quick and kind of impulsive in talking, and he said what he had to say very quickly,
[SPEAKER_02]: and earnestly, and I didn't sense much of a sense of humor in what he had to say.
[SPEAKER_02]: Occasionally he'd start chuckling about something that obviously he needed chuckling about, but he's very serious, and this is all business.
[SPEAKER_02]: And there goes an airplane overhead.
[SPEAKER_00]: He can do more traffic than a Washington airplane.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you sense that a little bit?
[SPEAKER_00]: They're both like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think they're both very hypertension and I think they're both very nervous and they're just very quick emotional giants.
[SPEAKER_00]: I imagine that when they really get going you're probably a virile laugh.
[SPEAKER_02]: Every question I ask he came right back real quickly with a very full detail but a staccato almost like response.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I think it's just their nature.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because she talked up the storm.
[SPEAKER_00]: The telephone rang?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, the telephone rang.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she was carrying on this conversation with this Doris, who was talking about her roles and her Cadillac and everything, and where they were going to take it to get it fixed.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Doris wanted to go out, and then she started asking me questions.
[SPEAKER_00]: What were some of those?
[SPEAKER_02]: She wanted to know... What did Doris want to know?
[SPEAKER_00]: Doris wanted to know...
[SPEAKER_00]: what Gene did, where he taught, what he taught, and all this is being relayed on the phone from me to Mrs. Doris.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Doris says, oh, she said, yes, his wife is in here with me, and I just feel like I've known her for years.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then the window man came, which kind of ended our conversation, because she was trotting around there.
[SPEAKER_00]: But every year they've lived down there.
[SPEAKER_00]: She goes grocery shopping on Thursday and gets her hair done on Friday, and the only time she ever canceled it was when Kennedy was assassinated.
[SPEAKER_00]: Why was that?
[SPEAKER_00]: Did she know something?
[SPEAKER_00]: Because she had gotten this letter from her daughter.
[SPEAKER_00]: It had some stupendous news in it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I wonder if she was coming home or something like that.
[SPEAKER_02]: She was a nun by then.
[SPEAKER_02]: A nun, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: She'd been a nun for many years.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, does that wrap up Tony Cooch?
[SPEAKER_02]: I think that wraps up Tony Cooch.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now can we talk about Milton Gast?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I was about to say about that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Okay.
[SPEAKER_02]: This interview ended around 11.15, so Tony could get off of his golf match with Al Lopez.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think that was at 11.00.
[SPEAKER_01]: 11.30.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, maybe not.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was really rushed at the end there, I know that.
[SPEAKER_02]: I did manage to get a picture or two taken of him and me.
[SPEAKER_02]: I went racing out of the car to get the camera, and the camera wasn't there.
[SPEAKER_02]: I came racing back in.
[SPEAKER_02]: Reed had it all the time.
[SPEAKER_02]: We could have saved a few minutes.
[SPEAKER_02]: But then we left and drove leisurely through St. Petersburg, through Tampa, and over the... You tried to see Fred Lee.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, we went over the long bridge to St. Petersburg.
[SPEAKER_02]: About 12 o'clock it was, I think, when we got to the Oak Lodge at 235 3rd Avenue North in St. Petersburg, down near the bay.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I went up to see if Fred Lieb was there, and there was an old gentleman, an old lady on the porch there.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I asked him, is Fred Lieb here?
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, oh no, he's gone to Houston.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I knew, of course, at once that he was going to stay with his daughter in Houston.
[SPEAKER_02]: And then I had quite a chat with this old gentleman who was born about six months after Fred Lieb, in 1888.
[SPEAKER_02]: They were both 91.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he said that about six months ago Fred realized that he wasn't able to take care of himself very well.
[SPEAKER_02]: He'd walk down the street and fall down for no reason.
[SPEAKER_02]: Fred would say, I wasn't dizzy though, I just fell down.
[SPEAKER_02]: So he thought it was time that somebody in the family could take care of him.
[SPEAKER_02]: So he decided to leave then.
[SPEAKER_02]: So he went over to Houston and that was the end of that.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'd hoped to be able to chat with him briefly and at least say hello to him.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then we drove a little bit farther downtown into the Bay Area in St. Pete, and we took some pictures of Al Lang Field, the new Al Lang Field, which has been built just in the last few years.
[SPEAKER_02]: The Al Lang Field, which was there back in 1969 when I was here my only other time, was no longer standing.
[SPEAKER_02]: Some old gentleman came by and said, you know, they built a new one, and I said,
[SPEAKER_02]: The Cardinals and the Mets player, he says, yeah, he says, you're all 79 years old or older.
[SPEAKER_02]: That took care of that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Youngest one's 79 years old, he said, and I thanked him very much and went on his way.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was about 83, I guess.
[SPEAKER_02]: And so I walked around and drove around and we took a picture of the stadium from where the signs show.
[SPEAKER_02]: Then we drove around the Bay Center, which has the Ringling Brothers Circus right now, this week.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's down there at the Bay Center, a huge convention center.
[SPEAKER_02]: It must have been built about the same time the new outlying field was built.
[SPEAKER_02]: I drove back and we drove down the street trying to find all those stockbrokers' offices, but couldn't find them, so we headed for the Bay.
[SPEAKER_02]: And we took this trip across the bay, this 14 or 15 mile... ...bay, this 14 or 15 mile bridge, which cost only 50 cents over from St. Pete to Bradenton, or to actually Palmetto.
[SPEAKER_02]: We got to Bradenton, and...
[SPEAKER_02]: Went into Bradenton for a little while.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was about 1 o'clock.
[SPEAKER_02]: We saw it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Kind of heavy traffic, wasn't it?
[SPEAKER_02]: I guess it was a little bit later.
[SPEAKER_02]: We saw the restaurant there, the Lantern Restaurant.
[SPEAKER_02]: And we went in and there were all kinds of Chinese figures on that wall.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I asked the gentleman first if they had American food.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said yes, so I went and had an egg foo yonk.
[SPEAKER_02]: And we got Duffy, one of the waitresses, to tell us where
[SPEAKER_02]: You went out and called?
[SPEAKER_02]: I went out and called Milt Gaston and got him.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was very congenial.
[SPEAKER_02]: Come on out.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I asked the waitress where he lived, and she didn't know, but it was the Oak Villas.
[SPEAKER_02]: I thought it was Oak Village, but she had the right dope, and she said, go on down this road, a five-stop, it was traffic lights, then cut left to 29th Avenue, and then go over and wait.
[SPEAKER_02]: So we had our egg foo yong and you had shrimps.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was a pretty good lunch.
[SPEAKER_02]: It wasn't very expensive, was it?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was kind of hot in there, but it was nice.
[SPEAKER_02]: Because we didn't get all our clothes on.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, we still were.
[SPEAKER_02]: I had about three sweaters on.
[SPEAKER_02]: She had all her thermal underwear and some of her thermal outerwear on.
[SPEAKER_00]: My stocking cap.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had changed in the walk-off.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was cold last night.
[SPEAKER_02]: I was down about my first sweater by this time.
[SPEAKER_02]: And... You know, I haven't been out of these clothes for two days.
[SPEAKER_02]: You didn't have to.
[SPEAKER_02]: You changed.
[SPEAKER_02]: No, I didn't change.
[SPEAKER_02]: I just changed my pants.
[SPEAKER_02]: I got my underwear still on.
[SPEAKER_02]: I got to take a shower and I'm reeking.
[SPEAKER_02]: We both reek, though, so we don't notice it.
[SPEAKER_02]: And so we got on the road after our egg foo young down Route 41 to the fifth stoplight.
[SPEAKER_02]: And of course I turned off at the fourth stoplight because that said follow route 41 and 41 went left at the fourth stoplight.
[SPEAKER_02]: It took a half hour to get back on the right road.
[SPEAKER_02]: The traffic was bumper to bumper for almost a couple hundred yards.
[SPEAKER_02]: You'd have to wait two or three changes in the light.
[SPEAKER_02]: I had to make the turn.
[SPEAKER_02]: I realized I was in the wrong lane before I ever got to the second change of light.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I had to swing around.
[SPEAKER_02]: Made it back through, I cheated though, I cut through a shopping center and saved about 20 seconds, I think, to get back there.
[SPEAKER_02]: And we got back on the right road and went down to the fifth stoplight.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I told Milt Gasper...
[SPEAKER_00]: When are my ginger ales all gone?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, what are you drinking my ginger ale for?
[SPEAKER_02]: You see me drinking it here?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: When did I drink that?
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'm glad you saw me.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I said we'd be there about three because we'd have to eat and then find a motel or a campground.
[SPEAKER_02]: We couldn't find a motel and we ate so we went there and got there about 2.30.
[SPEAKER_02]: Went to the fifth light and it was the Oak Villas and we couldn't find it.
[SPEAKER_02]: We went around the villa round and round in there.
[SPEAKER_02]: These are houses behind houses.
[SPEAKER_02]: Finally some lady told us where it was.
[SPEAKER_02]: And there was milk coming out tall,
[SPEAKER_02]: slim, trim, energetic, looking a little bit like 83, maybe, but full of vigor and pleasant and outgoing and in full control of everything.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he invited us in and we had a very delightful... Oh, it must have been about two hours there, I suppose.
[SPEAKER_02]: I got about an hour and a half tape.
[SPEAKER_02]: There's a little bit left on it, but I thought we'd fill in the comments on this tape now and make this a
[SPEAKER_02]: a comment tape, since we've got a little bit of comment space left.
[SPEAKER_02]: Comment.
[SPEAKER_00]: Why don't you say it louder?
[SPEAKER_00]: She went in to watch a soap opera just after we got there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Their house was nice, but it was much smaller.
[SPEAKER_02]: They had the TV on in the room we were talking with the soap operas on.
[SPEAKER_02]: He shut it off and sent her off into the other room.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, she went into the other room.
[SPEAKER_02]: She said, let's turn this thing off.
[SPEAKER_02]: I would have asked them to turn it off anyhow.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was a nice house, but their furniture was a little threadbare and worn and everything.
[SPEAKER_00]: Apparently they don't have any family.
[SPEAKER_00]: She always went to spring training with them, except
[SPEAKER_00]: But she didn't go on the road with him because she went between his family who lived in New Jersey and his sister in Boston.
[SPEAKER_00]: Those were the two she visited.
[SPEAKER_00]: She was very pleasant when she came back out.
[SPEAKER_00]: Got us a Coke, got Gina a beer.
[SPEAKER_02]: I left half a beer.
[SPEAKER_02]: That was the biggest beer I ever saw.
[SPEAKER_00]: A. Yeah, it was one of those big ones.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's the one they split, but I had this habit.
[SPEAKER_00]: I just took care of it.
[SPEAKER_02]: When I went in there, he showed me this.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know how it happened.
[SPEAKER_00]: M. You said you were a Cleveland Indian fan.
[SPEAKER_00]: A.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did I tell him on the phone, I wonder?
[SPEAKER_00]: M. No, you said that as soon as you went in.
[SPEAKER_02]: A.
[SPEAKER_02]: He came up awfully quickly with a Cleveland Indian scrapbook.
[SPEAKER_00]: M. And you said something about
[SPEAKER_00]: You were born in 21 and you'd always heard about the 1921 World Series.
[SPEAKER_02]: I said that much later.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, you said you were a Cleveland Indian.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had showed me that.
[SPEAKER_02]: The first thing he showed me was this little scrapbook.
[SPEAKER_02]: I've got it sitting over here.
[SPEAKER_02]: A lovely little scrapbook of the 1920 World Series, I'd say.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'd say 8 by 10, bound in hard...bound in leather.
[SPEAKER_02]: And inside it says, this sports scrapbook compiled and issued May 1st, 1953 to commemorate the 25th birthday of True Fit Screw Products Corporation.
[SPEAKER_02]: And it's presented to Milt Gaston, compliments of an admirer.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I just leaf through, this is about 50 pages.
[SPEAKER_02]: It has the story, the play-by-play,
[SPEAKER_02]: game highlights and boxcarts of every game of the seven games of the 1920 World Series, plus pictures of players at that time and pictures of players in 1953.
[SPEAKER_02]: And it's beautifully done.
[SPEAKER_02]: They're copies of the newspaper stories, I'd say.
[SPEAKER_02]: Kind of Xerox-like, before Xerox was ever thought of.
[SPEAKER_02]: Done on a brown background.
[SPEAKER_00]: What if they were pasted in a scrapbook?
[SPEAKER_02]: It looks very much like it was a scrapbook and photographed.
[SPEAKER_02]: But it's all nicely done.
[SPEAKER_02]: And oh, I just envied that so much.
[SPEAKER_02]: And at the end of our interview, or during the interview, I said, you know, that 20 scrapbook reminds me of my own experience growing up, how I was born the year after, just six months after they won the pennant in the World Series, or seven months maybe.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I'd heard all about that for years and years, and they never would win another pennant until 48.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I just, I was doomed as a boy not to have a pennant there.
[SPEAKER_02]: And we talked a little bit about that.
[SPEAKER_02]: At the end of the thing, I said, that was a great book, I wish I could get a copy of that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Meaning, I hoped that I could talk to these people at the National True Fit Screw Products Corporation in Cleveland, see if I could get another copy.
[SPEAKER_02]: Take it.
[SPEAKER_01]: He said, take it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Rita tried to discourage him, but I had shut her up in a hurry.
[SPEAKER_02]: And then I asked him to write in it, and he wrote in the front there, to Gene from Milt Gaston, with all good wishes.
[SPEAKER_02]: So this is really a coup.
[SPEAKER_02]: But I'm the only person to save her with a copy of this.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I've had a lot of scrapbooks in the last few months about Cleveland Indians.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think Mrs. Gaston had a stroke.
[SPEAKER_00]: She was a little shaky.
[SPEAKER_02]: I have a picture of Mrs. Cranmer.
[SPEAKER_00]: There are a couple of pictures.
[SPEAKER_02]: There's one which says November 23, 1951.
[SPEAKER_02]: It must be love.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's Milt Gasson, a beautiful looking gal, which I think must be Mrs. Gasson, although she looks so much different today because of this stroke we think she may have had.
[SPEAKER_02]: Here's one from 1970.
[SPEAKER_02]: She's looking more like she does now.
[SPEAKER_02]: She's grey and she's drawn.
[SPEAKER_02]: and her emotions are a little bit more strained.
[SPEAKER_02]: But Milt Gaston, he's looking, he shows his age of course.
[SPEAKER_02]: He reminds me a little bit of Pinky Shoffner in his build and in the facial structure.
[SPEAKER_02]: I think he was about this age too that time I saw him.
[SPEAKER_02]: We went into his bedroom after the interview and I took some pictures there.
[SPEAKER_02]: I took some pictures on my 35mm camera of pictures he had framed on the walls of he and his brother, one of Babe Ruth, one of him, I forgot what the other one was.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was Moe Berg, I believe it was one.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he brought out a little scrapbook, which was really more than a scrapbook, it was a photograph album of eight by ten pictures of players he had known and himself, neatly mounted with cellophane wrappers in each page.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I took a few pictures from there too.
[SPEAKER_02]: There'll be another, a better one of himself and his brother Alex.
[SPEAKER_02]: But I didn't take that because they were running out of film.
[SPEAKER_02]: I'd taken another one.
[SPEAKER_02]: I didn't know he had this one.
[SPEAKER_02]: I would have taken it.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was a better picture than the one I took.
[SPEAKER_02]: And there was a loose one, kind of a sepia picture tucked into this album, and I took a picture of that and he said, that's my favorite.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I told him then that if this came out, I hope it will, I'd be glad to send him a few copies because he gets all these inquiries from kids, you know, he doesn't have any pictures to send them.
[SPEAKER_02]: happy and willing to respond to kids' letters asking for autographs and pictures.
[SPEAKER_02]: He just doesn't have any pictures.
[SPEAKER_02]: He's the most congenial, friendly, honest person.
[SPEAKER_02]: I now recall a player who was so willing to admit he was wrong in things he did or said, in his performance.
[SPEAKER_02]: I didn't want to bring up his lifetime record, which was 97 victories and about 160 defeats.
[SPEAKER_02]: But as he said, he was with a losing team all the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd been with the Yankees or... What was he talking about, the year he had been earned running average in the 70s?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, the George Earnshaw.
[SPEAKER_02]: Actually, his earning average wasn't that good that year.
[SPEAKER_02]: I didn't want to bring it up.
[SPEAKER_02]: But his earning averages were much higher in those years.
[SPEAKER_02]: They've come down steadily with this, uh, platoon pitching.
[SPEAKER_00]: Uh, well, can we sign off now?
[SPEAKER_02]: No, we've got half a tape here to go.
[SPEAKER_02]: We've got 50 minutes to go.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, I just don't know if I can make that.
[SPEAKER_02]: We gotta...
[SPEAKER_02]: I never thought about it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now, uh...
[SPEAKER_02]: So this is Thursday night.
[SPEAKER_02]: We've been on our trip about a week.
[SPEAKER_02]: We left Thursday morning a week ago.
[SPEAKER_02]: That makes it about eight days, really.
[SPEAKER_02]: We've been in sunny Florida here.
[SPEAKER_02]: This day on Thursday, January 3rd, 1980, was a glorious day.
[SPEAKER_02]: And I'm sure if we were camping tonight, we'd thought about it, but it was a little late to...
[SPEAKER_00]: It was after five when we left the gas station.
[SPEAKER_02]: There was a campground here in Sarasota.
[SPEAKER_02]: which we thought of going to, but it was late.
[SPEAKER_02]: The way we set up tent last night, you know, it was about 20 minutes.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yesterday afternoon, it was about noon, we had to get to Busch Gardens.
[SPEAKER_02]: I never saw a tent go up so fast.
[SPEAKER_02]: We must have set a world record.
[SPEAKER_02]: We could have done that, I'm sure.
[SPEAKER_02]: We were weary from last night.
[SPEAKER_02]: It was a hard day today.
[SPEAKER_02]: Exhilarating as it was, it was a hard day.
[SPEAKER_02]: A lot of driving and finding places to go to.
[SPEAKER_02]: Are you supposed to get cold tonight?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's warmer here than way up north in Tampa.
[SPEAKER_00]: You should have explained about the oranges.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, you've got a few minutes here if you want to explain.
[SPEAKER_02]: When there's a frost, there's an orange frost.
[SPEAKER_02]: She was not talking about what our neighbor told us last night, Timmy's father.
[SPEAKER_00]: They have smudge pots going and they have air blowing on them.
[SPEAKER_00]: to beat the frost off again.